softwaretestinghelp.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY**

 **Modification Date:** May 25, 2018

I (Vijay, founder of SoftwareTestingHelp.com) provide you with insight into the privacy practices employed here at softwaretestinghelp.com. Particular areas of the world now require different privacy disclosures, so please read the entire policy to make sure you understand our practices fully.

 **1\. If you are Located in the EU**

 **A. What Personal Data Do We Collect From You?**

Personal data is information that can be used to identify you such as your name, IP address, and email address. As a business, we collect personal data from you in a number of ways including:

  * Opt-In To Email throughout the site: Your email address.
  * Transaction: You name, email address, billing information and payment source.

 **B. What Is The Purpose of Processing Your Personal Data?**

We collect the information above for the following purposes.

  * Opt-In To Email throughout the site: To provide you with information on the latest updates, announcements, course details, promotions, the topic in question and the topic in general.
  * Transaction: To process a purchase you make with us.

 **C. What Legal Basis Do We Have For Collecting and Processing Your Information?**

Websites must have a legal basis for collecting information from individuals located in the European Union. Our legal basis for each of the ways we collect information from you is as follows. Please note where consent forms the basis, you can withdraw consent at any time by contacting Vijay by opting out of any email message using the “unsubscribe” link.

Opt-In To Email newsletter: We will ask for your consent first.  
Transaction: We will collect your information as part of a legal contractual transaction.

“Legitimate interests” for processing your personal information exist where you submit the information with an expectation that it will be processed and there is no undue impact on you. If you disagree or have questions, please contact Vijay at info@SoftwareTestingHelp.com and we will cease the processing of your data under this legal basis.

 **D. Who Has Access To The Data We Collect?**

We process and access to the data we collect from you. However, we use third parties to assist us with processing your personal data including the following categories of recipients:

Financial transaction processors (processing your payments)  
Customer service communication platform  
Email communication manager  
Website management services  
Website design and programming services

These third parties have a contract with us in which they are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than we dictate.

 **E. Cookies and Similar Technologies**

This site uses cookies and similar technologies to track particular aspects of you and other people who visit us. This tracking is done to provide us with information on how people move about the site, what is of interest to them and what is not, how our marketing is performing, and incidental items such as what percentage of users access the site from a personal computer versus a mobile phone. You may block most cookies by adjusting your browser settings as well as responding to the cookie consent notice that appears when you visit this site. Read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.softwaretestinghelp.com/cookie-policy/).

 **F. How Long Do We Keep Your Data?**

We keep your personal data for different periods of time depending on the reason it was gathered in the first place.  
Opt-In To Email newsletter: Until you or we unsubscribe you  
Transaction: Four years

If a legal claim arises involving your data, we will store and disclose that data until the matter has resolved.

 **G. Your Right To Ask For Corrections, Erasure, And Export Of Your Data**

You have the right to control your personal data. Specifically, you have the following rights:

The right to be informed: We are informing you now with this policy.  
The right of access: We’ll provide you with the data we have about you.  
The right to rectification: Request we fix incorrect data about you.  
The right to erasure: Request we erase certain data about you.  
The right to restrict processing: Ask us to restrict certain type of processing of your personal information.  
The right to data portability: Ask us to provide your personal data we have for export.  
The right to object: Object to how we use your data.  
Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling: We don’t profile you, but keep in mind you have this right with other sites.  
To exercise any of these rights, please contact Vijay at Info@Softwaretestinghelp.com with your request.

 **H. Your Right To Withdraw Consent**

Although this is mentioned above, we want to emphasize that wherever we’ve asked for your consent to collect or process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent. If you receive email messages from us, you can use the “unsubscribe” link in each message to withdraw consent and stop the mailings. Alternatively, you can contact Vijay at Info@Softwaretestinghelp.com with your request.

 **I. Privacy Concerns, Contacting Us, Complaints.**

You can contact Vijay at Info@Softwaretestinghelp.com with your request with any questions or requests you have about these policies or your personal data.

Data Controller

Representative: Vijaykumar Shinde  
SoftwareTestingHelp.com  
SoftwareTestingHelp.org  
1104, Tuscan, Kharadi, Pune, India – 411028

***************************

 **2\. For All our valued Friends regardless of the Location:**

 **What information do we collect?**

We collect information from you when you place an order, subscribe to our newsletter or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name or e-mail address and payment information details like credit card info. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

 **What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

 **To personalize your experience**  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)

 **To improve our website**  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)

 **To improve customer service**  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)

 **To process transactions**

Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

 **To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature**

 **To send periodic emails**

The email address you provide for order processing may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

 **Note:** If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

 **How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information.

 **Do we use cookies?**

Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. Read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.softwaretestinghelp.com/cookie-policy/).

 **Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

 **Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We, therefore, have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **Children's Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products, and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

 **Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website.

 **Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our [privacy policy](https://www.softwaretestinghelp.com/privacy/).

 **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

 _This policy was last modified on 25th May 2018._

 **[Contact us](https://www.softwaretestinghelp.com/contact/) for any queries.**
